# Liz Bilashaka



## Quality Assurance Specialist + ISTQB Certified Tester

**Phone:** +64210606840

E-mail: lizbilashaka@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/lizbilashaka/

WWW https://lizb.net/

Dedicated software tester professional and quality assurance specialist with a history of meeting company goals utilizing consistent and organized practices. Skilled in working under pressure and adapting to new situations and challenges to best enhance the organizational brand. Familiar with handling multiple projects in highly competitive environments. Great interpersonal and collaboration skills.

### **Work History**

#### November 2021 -Current

#### **Manual Software Tester**

GameZovah, Auckland, New Zealand

- Write and optimize test cases to maximize success of functional and nonfunctional software testing with consistent, thorough approaches.
- Assessed software bugs and compiled findings along with suggested resolutions for development team members.
- Supported test review, defect control and configuration management within delivery pipeline.
- Defined and identified test cases for new application development.
- Optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing.
- API testing
- Verified acceptance by developing and implementing automated and manual application features and regression tests.
- Collaborated with QA team to test software quality through manual and automated testing.
- Wrote and optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing with consistent, thorough approaches.
- Coordinated work with various teams to solve problems and improve efficiency for software testing and automation.
- Assisted team with development of web-based applications in Agile environment.

## March 2022 – September 2022

## **Customer Service Advisor**

Xplor Technologies, Auckland, New Zealand

• Aiding clients and companies with billing enquire

- Assist customers in making payment plans through analyzing their financial circumstances
- Updating customer information in the company database
- Performing administrative tasks as assigned by the Supervisor
- Follow up with customer accounts to ensure overdue accounts are cleared
- Follow up on correspondence between customers and companies to ensure that both parties are on the same page
- Managed over 50 customer calls per day.

#### November 2020 – January 2021

## **Platform Success Manager**

Digital Oracles, Manchester, United Kingdom

- Competitor analysis keep the competitor analysis updated, in terms of funding received, team size, products
- Created a line of communication with investor and startups to ensure great customer satisfaction
- Oversaw BETA launch of the platform
- Create an internal weekly dashboard analyzing the speed of growth of startups, success rate of startups, overall feedback, number of perks available, number of resources and tools, revenue coming from revs and tools, revenue coming from investors
- Create an Investor update analyzing the number of deals performed, Assets under management, Industries, and business models (B2B, B2C, SaaS, e-commerce, etc.)
- Analyze lists of accelerators and demo the platform to them
- Deliver content for the online platform

### January 2016 – September 2019

## **Business Analyst**

AHBS. Auckland. New Zealand

- Conducted interviews with key business users to collect information on business processes and user requirements.
- Improved business direction by prioritizing customers and implementing changes based on collected feedback.
- Analyzed key aspects of the business to evaluate factors driving results and summarized them into presentations.
- Delivered analysis of market, sales and consumer trend impact on long and short-term strategies.
- Interacted with internal customers to understand and translate business needs into requirements and project scope.

- Generated business intelligence reports to inform strategic decision-making.
- Assessed business requirements to forecast annual budgetary operational costs.
- Applied honed problem-solving skills to analyze and resolve issues impacting business operations and goal achievement.
- Analyzed open orders, backlog, and sales data to provide the sales team with insights.

# **June 2014 - November 2015**

#### Sales Assistant

AHBS, Auckland

- Assisted customers with prompt and polite support in person and via telephone.
- Used consultative sales techniques to understand customer needs and recommend relevant products and services.
- Entered, coded and processed vendor invoices and helped track expenses for capitalizations.
- Collaborated with sales and marketing teams to establish an accurate representation of products marketed to customers.
- Composed routine correspondence and prepared reports or replies to requests for information within areas of responsibility.
- Maintained current knowledge of evolving changes in the marketplace.
- Drove store revenue by offering customers accessories and related purchases to complete selections.
- Attended monthly sales meetings and quarterly sales training.

#### Technical skills

HTML5	CSS3	JavaScript	Bootstrap	React
Technical Writing	Testing plans	Bug tracking	Test implementation	Defect monitoring
Manual test case preparation	Postman	Regression Testing Understanding	Test Planning	Background In Agile Environments
Debugging	Cross-Platform Testing	Project Management	Jira	Selenium
Automation experience	Business process mapping	SQL and databases	Quality assurance	

#### Education

**ISTOB** Certified Tester Foundation Level

Skillsoft - Online

2022-02 - 2022-11 Bachelor of Business (1st Honors): Information Systems

Auckland University of Technology - Auckland, AUK

2019-02 - 2021-11 Bachelor of Business: Information Systems

Auckland University of Technology - Auckland, AUK

#### **Additional Skills**

Ability to work under pressure Strong interpersonal skills Excellent communication skills

Team player Fast Learner Attention to detail

Able to learn and adapt to new Strong oral and written skills Excellent in working in a multicultural

environment

### Referee

technology

Provided upon request